ILGWU. Jay Mazur papers, 5780/203
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series II. Subject files
  - NYC, 1984-1986 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    See also Koch, Mayor 1985-1990; see also NYC – Commercial Rent Control 1984-1989; see also NYC Industrial Loft Advisory Council Memo from Mayor Ed Koch to all agency heads re city policy on undocumented aliens, noting that for the sake of the common good, they should be encouraged to use city services such as medical care and education, and that the city has no obligation to report them to federal authorities, with cover note to Mazur from ILGWU officer Muzaffar Chishti, October 15, 1985; agenda of Refugee Employment Project Advisory Board, October 15, 1985, with agenda for conference, November 1; New York Migration Forum meeting agendas, June 1984, and bulletin re Simpson-Mazzoli immigration bill, refugee act, December 22, 1983; proposal by mayor's office to NYS Science & Technology Foundation for creation of Industrial Innovation Extension Service, with cover letter to Mazur, July 29, 1986; memos re commercial rent control, 1984; memo from mayor's office re city's industrial retention program, January 30, 1984; related correspondence, including from NYC comptroller Harrison J. Goldin, December 14, 1984; letter to Mazur from Mayor Koch appointing him to the Industrial Loft Advisory Council, June 28, 1984; position papers by Dinkins '85 for Manhattan Borough President campaign re jobs and economic development, zoning and physical overdevelopment, saving garment industry jobs, with cover letter to Mazur from ILGWU officer Susan Cowell; letter to Mazur from City Council president Carol Bellamy asking for support for Day Care Fund (report attached), program to assist employers in providing child care services for employees, January 24, 1984; letter from Bellamy to ILGWU local official Edgar Romney re city-wide after-school program, February 7, 1985; statement by City Council president Carol Bellamy, in favor of asbestos safety legislation, November 14, 1985; list of endorsers of asbestos legislation; correspondence re councilman race in Queens between two factions of the county Democratic committee, both labor-friendly, July 1985; letter to Mazur from Sal Albanese of Brooklyn, asking for endorsement in councilman race, June 10, 1985; letter from Mazur to members of the City Planning Commission in support of banning transient hotels in the SoHo/Chinatown area to preserve manufacturing use of district, January 24, 1985
  - NYC-42nd Street Development Project, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    See also NYC Garment Center Special District Testimony 1986-1987; see also Abeles Schwartz Associates 1983-1984 Statement by Mazur before the Board of Estimate at hearing on industrial retention and relocation, opposing grants to firms that leave Manhattan, August 16, 1984; letter from the Apparel Manufacturers Association to the NYC Office of Business Development, objecting to the proposed Industrial Retention Program giving grants to firms leaving Manhattan, August 13, 1984; summary of Board of Estimate Statement; Testimony by Mazur on the Draft Environmental Impact Statement for the 42nd St. Redevelopment Project, March 26, 1984; Comments on the Draft Environmental Impact Statement for the 42nd St. Redevelopment Project, submitted to the NYS Urban Development Corp. by the ILGWU, May 1984; testimony by Mazur at the UDC hearing on the 42nd St. Redevelopment Project, September 6, 1984; index cards with talking points re economic impact of garment center; press release, Statement by Mayor Edward I. Koch, Comptroller Harrison J. Goldin and City Council President Carol Bellamy re Times Square redevelopment and garment center, November 8, 1984; newspaper clippings; handwritten notes
  - Board of Education, NYC, 1988-1991 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    Letter to principal of Norman Thomas High School for Commercial Education thanking Mazur for contribution of $250 for a scholarship, May 23, 1991; letter from Mazur to Robert F. (Bobby) Wagner, Jr., on his appointment as NYC Schools Chancellor, October 3, 1989; list of industrial literacy, skills training, and English as a Second Language programs conducted by the ILGWU for presentation to schools chancellor Richard Green, June 17, 1988
  - NYC Congressional Tour and Fashion Show, 1987-1991 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    Tour of New York City offered biennially to new members of Congress featuring an ILGWU-sponsored fashion show of apparel produced in New York City. Letters from Mazur to NYC mayor Ed Koch and other officials inviting them to attend the show, April 13, 1987; letter to Mazur from Rep. Charles Rangel, noting that 68 members of Congress would attend, May 1, 1989; list of companies represented and fashion items presented; agenda of all tour events; remarks by Mazur (?); memo to Mazur from ILGWU legislative director Evelyn Dubrow re need to put on a less expensive show, recommending against sponsorship by Philip Morris, January 8, 1991
  - NYC Commercial Rent Control, 1984-1989 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    See also NYC Garment Center Special District; see also NYC Industrial Loft Advisory Council; see also Speeches – NYC Commercial Rent Hearings 1989; see also Speeches – Garment Center 2001; see also Koch, Mayor 1985-1990; see also NYC 1984-1986 Memo to ILGWU exec. asst. James Parrott outlining arguments for preserving manufacturing in NYC, April 28, 1988; memo from Mazur to ILGWU NYC managers re union's support of Intro. 914, January 15, 1988, with attached fact sheet, flyer for coalition event, and testimony by Mazur at City Council hearing, December 1, 1987; summary of commercial rent arbitration bill by sponsor councilwoman Ruth Messinger: "Statement on Discharge of Intro. #1237," June 13, 1989; Memorandum in Opposition to Intro. 2345 and in support of Intro. 914-A by the Federation of Apparel Manufacturers (Eli Elias, president), June 14, 1989; City of New York Office of the Mayor Memorandum in Support of state legislation to amend the Public Service Law limiting electricity surcharges imposed by landlords to commercial tenants, May 9, 1989, with cover letter to Mazur urging lobbying support, sample letter, list of key legislators, May 23, 1989; ILGWU Testimony, City Council Hearings on Commercial Rent Control, December 11, 1986; memo from Parrott to Mazur re ACTWU contribution to commercial rent campaign, need to speak to ACTWU president Jack Sheinkman for more, lack of donations from musicians, printers unions, April 13, 1989; letter to Mazur from Sheinkman suggesting they work together on commercial rent problem, June 1, 1984; memo to Mazur from Susan Cowell re commercial rent control and related legislative efforts, May 23, 1984; newspaper clippings
  - NYC Commission on the Status of Women, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    Letter from the NYC Commission on the Status of Women to ILGWU secretary-treasurer Irwin Solomon seeking financial support for CAW Fund, Inc., established to raise additional dollars, with description of programs, list of corporate and foundation contributors, newspaper clippings, February 1, 1988
  - NYC Economic Development Corp., 1994 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    See also Garment Industry Development Corporation; see also NYC – City Council – Economic Development Committee 1993; see also Speeches – Manufacturing Matters in NYC 1990; see also NYC – Workforce Development Commission 1993; see also NYC – Office of Business Development; see also Speeches – Levine, Randy – Talking Points 1997 Talking points for Mazur for meetings with Clay Lifflander, president, NYC Economic Development Corp., August 23 and October 8, 1994; letter to Lifflander, expressing disappointment over several canceled meetings, noting previous working relationship with every head of EDC since its creation, September 22, 1994; proposal for Giuliani administration, "A Public/Private Partnership for the New York Apparel Industry," describing history of NY labor partnerships, including the Garment Industry Development Association (GIDC), Council for American Fashion (CAF), Fashion Exports/New York (FE/NY), collaborations with the Fashion Institute of Technology, and others; related correspondence; newspaper clipping
  - NYC Economy-NAFTA (Box 19, Folder 2)
    "NAFTA and New York: Not Made for Each Other," by Jay Mazur, n.d.
  - NYC- Fashion Center Annual Report, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    See also Garment Industry Development Corporation Annual report, 1994-95, of the Fashion Center Management Association, Inc., the manager of the Fashion Center Business Improvement District; includes budget, security incidents, letters from business owners, newspaper clippings
  - NYC- Made in NYC Fashion Industry proposal, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    See also NYC Economic Development Corporation 1994; see also Garment Industry Development Corporation Proposals by Mazur for a "Made in New York City" campaign to promote the fashion industry and for an in-house city government "think tank" for economic development and related (housing, education) policy; op-ed piece by Mazur urging greater financial support by city government of apparel manufacturing sector, c. 1990
  - NYC Garment Center Special District, 1986-1987 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    See also NYC – Commercial Rent Control; see also NYC Industrial Loft Advisory Council; see also NYC 42nd St. Redevelopment Project 1984; see also Abeles Schwartz Associates 1983-1984; see also Local 23-25 – Garment Center Rally 1962-1972 Letters from Mazur to Gerald Shaw, president of Oscar de la Renta and others, urging them to testify in support of creating a Garment Center Special District, which would preserve manufacturing in perpetuity within the city's traditional garment district, March 9; Statement of Jay Mazur, president, ILGWU, on the Garment Center Special District, Board of Estimate Hearing, March 26, 1987; garment center fact sheet; letter from Mazur to Assemblyman Jerrold Nadler re Nadler's support for zoning to preserve manufacturing as expressed in his letter to the Village Voice, December 9, 1986 (attached)
  - NYC-Manufacturing "White Paper", 1990 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    See also Garment Industry Development Corporation; see also Council for American Fashion Second draft and final (?) bound "A Comprehensive Approach to New York City Apparel Manufacturing Development Policy," submitted by the ILGWU, March 1990, with cover memo to Mazur from exec asst James Parrott
  - NYC, Mayoral Race 1993, NY1 NewsPoll (Box 19, Folder 7)
    see also Dinkins; see also Giuliani Weekly poll results conducted by Lou Harris of LH Research for New York 1 News, division of Time Warner Entertainment (sponsored by NYNEX Corporation) of residents' attitudes on a multitude of variables in Giuliani-Dinkins race, other issues, March-October; questions on survey form for June 15-17; handwritten notes by Mazur
  - NYC, Deputy Mayor, Lynch, Bill, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    Correspondence with Bill Lynch, deputy mayor of New York under David Dinkins, re exploitation of workers by Williamsburg Trade Association, February 1, 1990; visit by British Labour Party head Neil Kinnock, November 9, 1989; meeting with Sanford Garelik, executive director, Garment Industry Security Council, June 5, 1990; budget for Garment Industry Development Corp. (GIDC), June 11, 1990; appointment of ILGWU representative to New York City Loft Board, February 15, 1990; handwritten notes by Mazur
  - NYC- Pinero, Sally Hernandez, Deputy Mayor, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    Letter to NYC Mayor Dinkins, copied to Deputy Mayor Pinero, re the Business Relocation Assistance Corporation (BRAC) and the need to change the policies of the Koch administration, which discouraged retention of apparel manufacturing in Manhattan, September 20, with attached statement by Mazur before the NYC Planning Commission, September 11; letter from Mazur to Pinero suggesting meeting re economic development policies with Wallace Ford, commissioner, Office of Business Services, and Paul Marinaccio, executive director, Economic Policy and Marketing Group, July 12; outline of notes in preparation for September 27 meeting with Ford and Marinaccio; draft notes from August 16 meeting with Pinero and David Smith, commissioner, Office of Business Development; letter to Mayor Dinkins from Rogi Equities & Investors (dba Chop Chop Cutting Services) threatening to move out of state unless the city provides a tax rebate, June 17; charts showing New York City apparel employment; memo to Mazur from ILGWU exec asst James Parrott reporting finding by Kurt Salmon Associates that out-of-town buyers inject at least $100 million annually into the NYC economy, September 26; outline of notes, "NYC 1991: World's Capital in Transition"; letter from Mazur to Pinero re city's efforts to save Mademoiselle Knitwear from bankruptcy, urging that rights of workers be considered, March 26
  - NYC- Pinero, Sally Hernandez, Deputy Mayor, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    see also Garment Industry Development Corporation "A Comprehensive Approach to New York City Apparel Manufacturing Development Policy," submitted by the ILGWU, March 1990; letter to Mazur from Deputy Mayor Pinero agreeing with his support for relocating Marlene Sportswear to the Brooklyn Army Terminal, April 17, 1990; letter from Mazur to Pinero re city's favorable tax treatment of Domsey Trading Corporation, engaged in anti-union activity, asserting that public funds should be used to further quality, not just quantity, of jobs, June 11; memos to Mazur from ILGWU exec asst James Parrott outlining items for discussion during meetings with Pinero and Mayor Dinkins, June 11 and August 16; fact sheets re importance of garment manufacturing industry for NYC; memo from Mazur to Mayor Dinkins and Deputy Mayor Bill Lynch summarizing points discussed at June 8 meeting re restoration of funding to Garment Industry Development Corporation (GIDC), promoting "Made in NY" apparel, holding a mini-summit on apparel manufacturing policy, exploring a mixed- use development in the Bronx, and other economic development issues, June 11; letter from Mazur to Dinkins urging continued funding of GIDC, May 7; memo to Mazur from Parrot re GIDC budget for FY 1991; "A Proposal to Promote New York City's Fashion Industry," submitted by the ILGWU, August 14; copy of cover story from Women's Wear Daily, "SA to City Hall: Give Us Respect, and a Lot More," with note from Mazur to Pinero, asking her to call him, July 17; invitation from Mazur for Pinero to address the Council for American Fashion (CAF), June 13; letter from Mazur to Pinero seeking clarification re mayor's Small Business Assistance plans, October 17
  - NYC- City Council, Economic Development Committee, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    Statement by Mazur before the New York City Council Committee on Economic Development endorsing city's "Strong Economy, Strong City" report, October 18, 1993
  - NYC-City Council- Finance Division, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    Notice of Executive Budget hearings for fiscal year 1995, with attached schedule for agency hearings; list of officials of NYC Central Labor Council, AFL-CIO
  - NYC- City Council Race, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    Letters to Mazur from several candidates for NY City Council, asking for ILGWU endorsement, with campaign literature; schedule of candidate interviews by ILGWU, August 8, 1991; spreadsheet analysis of races in all 51 districts, showing status of seat (incumbent strength), names of candidates, ethnic composition of neighborhoods and ethnic percentage breakdown of registered voters, concentration of ILGWU members or retirees, number of petition signatures obtained, amount of money raised, some positions on issues
  - NYC-City Planning Commission, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    See also Speeches – Manufacturing Matters in NYC 1990 Notes to Mazur from vp Susan Cowell re hearing by City Planning Commission on Garment Center zoning plan, January 28, 1988; letter from Mazur to chair of City Planning Commission expressing interest in participating in planning for the next half-century of NYC, September 13, 1988
  - New York City Central Labor Council, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    Copy of letter (in English, Spanish, and Chinese) from Mazur sent to all ILGWU members and retirees in NY metropolitan area in support of striking workers at Daily News, calling for boycott, with cover letter to New York City Central Labor Council, November 7, 1990; mailgram from Gus Bevona, president of Local 328-32J, SEIU, to NYC Central Labor Council president Tommy Van Arsdale urging support of striking doormen, porters, and other building maintenance members of, April 22, 1991; Labor Council Alert fact sheet re Campaign for Justice in Brooklyn supporting ILGWU organizing efforts against Williamsburg Trade Association, and letter from Mazur offering thanks, January 24, 1990; letter to Mazur from Victor Gotbaum soliciting financial support for the Center for Labor-Management Policy Studies, Graduate School, City University of New York (CUNY), with attached description of center and major projects, May 31, 1990; letter re second annual Asian Labor Festival, sponsored by the Asian Labor Committee of the NYC Central Labor Council, July 19, 1990; letter from Van Arsdale re labor activities supporting Dinkins mayoral campaign, July 21, 1989; flyer publicizing march on Washington, D.C. demanding affordable housing, October 7; memo to AFL-CIO Finance Committee from secretary-treasurer Thomas Donahue re debt problems with United Labor Agency in Washington, D.C., April 17, 1989; manuscript, "Rebuilding a Presidential Majority," by William A. Galston, University of Maryland, with cover note to Mazur from Ted H. Jacobsen, secretary of the NYC Central Labor Council, March 31, 1989; letter to Mazur from Van Arsdale re planned discussion at Executive Board meeting of the changing political situation re candidates for NYC mayor, January 10, 1989; recommendations of candidates for congressional and state office, April 23, 1990; appeal to Mazur for financial support for toys for children of striking machinists, December 11, 1989; letter to Mazur about providing office space for the New York chapter of Social Democrats USA, April 17, 1990
  - New York City Central Labor Council (AFL-CIO), 1988 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    Correspondence from Mazur to Tommy Van Arsdale, president, and other members of the New York City Central Labor Council re Labor Day parade, testimony in favor of commercial rent binding arbitration bill; draft of constitution and by-laws; page proof of pamphlet, "Human Rights for American Workers," published by the Trade Union Leadership Institute, New York City Central Labor Council, AFL-CIO, February 25
  - New York City Central Labor Council, 1985-1987 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    List of officers and Executive Board; roster of affiliates and member census; correspondence re needs assessment survey for workplace literacy programs, August 31, November 2, 1987; strike support for Federation of Professional Athletes, September 18, 1987; letters to members of Congress (Scheuer, Schumer, Solarz, Molinari, Green) re trade legislation, August 3, 1987, with reply from Molinari opposing "protectionism," August 14, 1987; letter withholding endorsement of Congressmen Schumer and Solarz for their refusal to override presidential veto of trade bill, October 29, 1986; letters of endorsement for candidates for Democratic district leaders; alert and flyer re strike at NBC by National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians; flyers for plant closing legislation; memos opposing hospital and nursing home ownership by out-of-state corporations; opposing use of foreign repair stations by U.S. commercial aircraft; letter to Mazur reporting on efforts to aid the trade bill, April 16, 1987; letter to Mazur re setting up political action committees in each borough, April 16, 1987; letter to Mazur re challenge by Victor Gotbaum to Central Labor Council constitution and election of officers, December 1, 1986; excerpt of minutes of Executive Board meeting of September 18, 1986, re purchase of tickets for annual dinner-dance of Black Trade Unionist Leadership Committee, opposition by Victor Gotbaum to ethnic caucuses as part of larger council; letter re increase in per capita dues, May 22, 1985
  - NYC- Industrial Loft Advisory Council, 1984-1987 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    See also NYC – Commercial Rent Control; see also NYC Garment Center Special District; see also Speeches – NYC Commercial Rent Hearing 1989; see also Speeches – Manufacturing Matters in NYC 1990; see also NYC 1984-1986; see also NYC 42nd St. Redevelopment Project 1984; see also Abeles Schwartz Associates 1983-1984 Letter to Mayor Ed Koch from James Gill, chairman of the Industrial Loft Advisory Council, re decline of manufacturing jobs, need to halt conversion of industrial space into commercial uses, April 11, 1986, with cover letter to Mazur; correspondence between Gill and commercial photographer Nancy Lowell McFarland re letter to Koch, with attached copy of local law imposing moratorium on rent increases on certain commercial properties, January 22, 1986, and cover letter from McFarland to Mazur, March 19, 1986; memo to Mazur from ILGWU vp Susan Cowell; minutes of eighth and ninth meetings, September 25, 1984, and February 6, 1985
  - NYC- Office of Business Development, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    See also Council for American Fashion; see also Garment Industry Development Corporation; see also NYC Economic Development Corporation 1994; see also NYC – Workforce Development Commission 1993; see also Speeches – Manufacturing Matters in NYC 1990; see also NYC 42nd St. Redevelopment Project 1984 Letter from Mazur to commissioner David A. Smith inviting him to attend meeting of Council for American Fashion (CAF)
  - NYC- Outsourcing, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - NYC--Westside Task Force, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    Memo to community workshop representatives re consensus of meeting about a number of planning issues, October 31, 1986
  - NYC-Workforce Development Commission, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    See also NYC – Economic Development Corporation 1994; see also NYC – Office of Business Development 1990; see also Garment Industry Development Corporation Confidential report to Mayor Dinkins from deputy mayor Barry Sullivan, who chaired the commission, focusing on education and training, December 28, 1998; includes list of members, including Mazur; dissenting letter from AFSME Disrict Council 37 executive director Stanley Hill
  - New York International Festival of the Arts, 1986-1991 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    Correspondence with Mazur re cultural event held in New York City, particularly first, held in 1987; newspaper clipping
  - New York State (NYS), 1983-1985 (Box 19, Folder 24)